Great.
It says: "Welcome to Hell".
WELCOME 6-CLASS (IN HELL)
This year is going to be poop.
How do you know?
Oops.  But something like that too.
I just know it.
Last year we were the kings.
Fifth graders.
We had this school under control.
Nobody likes us this year.
Yes that's true.
I stay out of it. I'm good.
I grow a mustache.
I see nothing.
Nope.
But it hit me worst of all.
Do you see that girl over there?
She will torment me at
every possible opportunity.
Wait a minute,
isn't that your sister?
Yes.
At least you have your own room.
My grandpa stole mine from me.
What? Your grandfather moved in with you?
When is that?
After his raid on the supermarket.
Can i help you sir
Yes, I want to see Maria.
Oh, Maria is gone.
We have switched to self-checkouts.
Much faster and more efficient.
You will like it.
Will it be cheaper if I
do all the work myself?
We have specials every day, sir.
Seriously? -Yes, sir.
Let me through. I want to go on.
-Please, no problem.
CASHBOX
Please scan an article.
-I'm talking to a robot.
I will do.
Let's see if that works.
Please scan an article.
You get into my Nerv.
Yes / Yes.
Sir  Sir
Sir, you should stop.
Wait, I'll help you up.
-My leg! Go away!
Now please, sir.
Go away! I am retired.
Get out of here.
I can judo! -Go away!
Leave the poor man alone!
Your shop sucks.
Are you insane?  Stop!
Oh, all right.
You want to mess with me.
You don't have more? That hurt.
There is my little one.
You didn't have to come here. I'm fine
What happened to the mailbox?
An idiot riveted him.
Oh shit.
Dad, are you driving again?
Your driver's license is gone, remember?
It's not gone,
I forgot to have it extended.
Now I'm supposed to take the driving
test, which is idiotic
because I've been driving for over 50
years. What am I supposed to do, starve?
I'm coming in now.
It just can't go on like this.
Do not worry.
This damn shop will never see me again.
No, I meant that I have
to leave everything behind
Drive two hours each
way just to check on you
I didn't ask you to come!
No, not you, but the police. Dad, I want
to come, I want to be there for you.
But maybe now is the time
to think about it...
No, I will not move!
I built and am doing this house
in here the last breath.
You don't put me in a home!
What if you moved in with us?
Are you crazy? Relatives are like fish
that stink after three days. Horrible ones
Idea. We'd kill ourselves.
Out of the question, sorry.
Dad!
I miss her too.
And nothing changes
if you let me
torn out of my house and
transplanted into yours.
Oh man.
Maybe we could
miss her together.
Yes, perhaps. But there is no room
in your house. Where would you put me
Under the roof?  Under no circumstance!
Now don't make it any harder than
it already is. It's the only choice.
Dad! If it's the only choice,
then it's not a choice at all.
"Choice" means you have to
choose between at least one
decide two things.
And that's just one.
Unless the other is
that I'm in the garden
sleep and be eaten by a bear.
Don't make a drama out of it now.
In addition,
your sisters already share a room.
Yes, Sarah already told me that.
You live in the clouds,
because your way is so far.
Wait a moment.  Shh!
Shh!
Shh...
Hey I'm back again. - Shh!
There is no bathroom in the attic. And
Grandpa doesn't manage all of these levels.
And the basement... is the basement.
Ha! -What?
My Jordans!  They have new laces.
Hey Peter,
should we help you move?
Disappears!  This is still my room.
Not for long.
Get out of here!  Go away!  Go away!
Peter, I know it's not
ideal, but we are
a family there you have to
sacrifice for each other.
Sometimes pretty big sacrifices.
Listen. There you have a lot
more space than in this room.
Now the attic will
be your new room.
No, he won't. The attic remains
where you put things and then they
Forgets, like our old TV or the
exercise bike that Dad used to use.
Right.
What? I train with it.
Just see it as a new beginning, okay?
We'll clean up thoroughly and
maybe put some nice wallpaper on.
Your turtles wouldn't hurt
if you had a better view.
They like it that way.
There you have your privacy.
Do you still like that, honey?
Yes.
Grandpa!
Grandpa is here, Grandpa is
here, Grandpa everywhere.
How nice that Grandpa is coming
and he'll stay there forever. Hey
Hey And please remember: we
don't want to overwhelm Grandpa.
He should first settle down.
There's plenty of time to
talk to him over dinner.
Oh, I won't be here. -What?
What?  I'm studying with Russel.
"Learning" is still learning, isn't it?
It's not slang for anything else?
No dad. "Learning" is still learning.
And I got the okay from mom.
Grandpa!
Jenny!
Don't knock him over.
Oh man.
Hi, Grandpa. -Hello Mausezahn.
Ed.
Artie.
Where is your brother
Peter?
Peter!
Come on, let's help
Grandpa with his luggage.
Okay, give it to me.
-Let it be.
OK.  Then I'll take the suitcase.
He called me "Artie" again.
Please Arthur,
this is really not easy for him.
Hey grandpa.
Hey there you are  Look at you.
Look at you.
You grow faster than grass.
Oh, chic sneakers.
Thank you.  Do you like your room?
Yes, looks nice.
-Sure, because it's beautiful.
By far the nicest room
in the whole house.
Oh I know kid Listen, I didn't
want it to happen that way either.
Sometimes you have to make
sacrifices in a family.
You're right.  That's true.
Sometimes you are not even asked.
There we are already two.
Oh yes, be careful with the floorboards.
They're uneven.
I will think about it.  Thank you.
I'll see you later, Grandpa.
You can come visit me anytime.
In the attic...
where it is teeming with spiders and mice.
Peter!
-I didn't do anything!
So here we are.
You've been robbed, dude.
No, I was attacked.
The worst part is that I
can't even complain about it.
But you're complaining
a lot for that, Peter.
I mean at home because he's old
and we all love him and stuff.
You cannot let the
enemy take your booth.
You have to fight back and
stand up for your rights.
I do not have rights.
Everyone has rights. They are, uh...
un-something... has something
to do with pursuit of happiness.
That’s the constitution.
Yes, that would be great if
I lived in North America.
But apparently Burlington
Avenue is 153 in North Korea.
Did your parents know
this when buying a house?
What?
I wouldn't put up with that.
I would ask for my room back
or there would be a war.
"Or is there a war"?
Should he attack his grandfather?
Only secretly, of course, Emma.
He cannot fight him in the normal way
because his grandfather is strong,
is big and experienced, while Peter
is only weak and small. And dumb.
You're a bad friend.
Hi Steven.
Mom says you should put on your
flip-flops for a shower after exercising.
Not cool, Lisa.
My brother has athlete's foot.
Totally gross and contagious.
Contagious?
And gross.
Only six toes are affected.
That's a lot of toes, bro.
Hello grandpa.
Hello my sweetie.
Do you wanna play something?
I have "reindeer races"
I have "Christmas World",
I have "1-2-3 Christmas porridge".
Maybe, but not now, okay?
Do you want to see a movie
I have "Frosty the Snowman".
I do not think so. Okay, little mouse?
Maybe tomorrow?
OK.
What's the matter with Grandpa?
How so?  What happened?
He just doesn't want to do anything.
He's just staring out the window
but there's just this dead tree
Daddy always wants to cut down,
but he's not allowed to use the chainsaw.
Daddy can use the chainsaw
anytime, snail. OK?
He just decided to wait
until Mommy says it's okay.
Nothing is with Grandpa.
He's just very tired and
thinks a lot about Grandma.
All good okay
OK.
Go away, go away!
I hate my life.
Oh come now!
Ouch.
"Declaration of war.
When in the context of human
events a person vacates the room
steals from another person,
there is no choice but to war.
You have 24 hours.
Give me back what's mine here
or face the consequences.
Secret Warrior. "
Nice handwriting.
Bad? Not at all.
You know it's a change, so...
Who are you talking to
Uh, with Jerry, I'll be done soon.
No, I would really like
to, but I can't
I'm kind of stuck here  Yes.
Hello Jerry, Sally here.
Hey
He's not stuck here.
-What shoud that?
I can drop it off when I drive to work.
Listen again.
See you then, Jerry.
Are you going to be helicopter mom now?
Are you going to pack me
sandwiches with a note in it?
A note? Maybe you don't
like what it says.
I'll meet him another time,
don't feel like it now.
You haven't seen Jerry in years.
Now you live nearby.
That'll be nice.
I can't and I don't want to. I still have
something to do. I have to take care of that
Take care of light switches in my room.
Artie installed it upside down.
Did you!
Eat up.  We're going in 10 minutes.
Yeah mom
How are you grandpa Slept well?
Like a marmot. Thank you.
Is there no newspaper in the house?
Yes, there is.
Here you go.
Ahh, I can't read that.
Just make it bigger.  So.
Oh yeah.
Jenn...
How does she actually survive?
She doesn't eat anything.
No idea.  You have to go, Peter.
OK.  And?  No nightmares?
I?  No.
Sleep disorders?
I only have eight words
left on the screen.
Don't you want to talk to me about anything?
Now everything is gone!
What have I done? How...
Peter, I'm waiting!
Well, if you want to talk
later, we can do that.
Have fun at school.
Didn't he say anything about it?
Not a word.  One should get that.
And I don't get you, man.
I mean,
you just slip the
note under the door?
Maybe he hasn't read it yet.
Yes, he did. It was on his desk.
Maybe he's already forgotten?
It happens to old people.
This is happening to you, Steve.
Oops.  Well, something like that...
The trouble is,
you lost the element of surprise.
The attack must be immediate.
You have chili in your backpack.
- He knows that.
Yes.
Hi Steven.
Oh god no
You left your
braces in mom's car.
There's still a chocolate bar in
there, it looks like.
At least I hope it is.
See you afterwards.
Yes, it's a candy bar.
Are you making good progress, Arthur?
Great yeah  If you like big boxes.
The fame of this company is based on them.
Yes.  Yes, probably true.
Are you sure this is
the Walmart profile?
Walmart?  I thought this was for Kmart.
No, Walmart.
Oh man. I'm sorry.
I have so much on my mind right now.
My father-in-law moved in with
us, so...
No idea. Somehow he
doesn't think much of me.
He thinks I work for a
soulless group of companies
who are not interested
in worries and needs...
... of your employees.
I wish you a lot of fun.
How do I get home again?
Well, you could walk.
Or you can take this.
I already have a cell phone.
It's not a cell phone. I don't even
know exactly what that is. Put it in.
Okay,
that's a ride called "Lyft".
If you want to go home, just swipe
over and someone will pick you up.
You don't need any money,
you don't even have to talk to anyone.
Wipe.  Wipe over it.
Bye dad.
Oh!  Yes.
Greetings to Jerry for me.
-I will.
Holy shit is this all yours?
All young dreams come true here.
Are you crazy?
Guys can't afford that.
The pool table alone
costs six grand.
And you play with it all
Of course, of course.
What do you feel like doing first?
Play billiards? Gym or football?
And what the hell is that
It's a onewheel.
It's a lot of fun.
And you can drive that thing?
Shit yeah
Epic!
Should see me.
Wow!
Yo, Jerry! Oh!
I didn't know you had a visitor.
This is my old friend Ed.
Ed, hi, Danny.
My pleasure.
So are we going for a walk?
Yes.
Oh good. Because my masseuse
told me when I was the week
Take 10,000 steps,
then she meets me for coffee.
And you know what "coffee" means.
Coffee?
Yes, coffee.
Morning ladies.
Seriously, dude?
These yoga pants kill me again.
Why are you doing this?
What?  They think I'm cute.
Yeah, like, "Sweet, the old guys.
Still think they have a chance."
Hey  I'm a good catch.
I'm getting a great pension.
Two more years and I can ski for free.
Do you ski?
No, I do not. Tomorrow.
Beautiful morning.
How are you?  Lovely.
Yes, delightful.
Mention the pension next time.
As if you would ever ski.
So how is it with your daughter, Ed?
Okay. I have my grandson's room,
which he doesn't think is great.
He sent that to me yesterday.
"... no room,... no choice,... consequences".
Wow!  And your answer?
Nothing at all.
You want to let that go?
-You have to answer that.
This aggression requires a counterattack.
Semper fi .
You were in the marines?
Not me.  I just mean...
He's a kid.
He gets used to it and so do I.
I'm his grandfather,
so he won't do anything.
Are you crazy?  You have to do something...
"House thieves have forfeited the
right to a good night's sleep."
Peter?  Hey peter!
Grandpa.  Are you that?
Yes, it's me and you know it.
Do you know what time it is?
Bedtime?
It's the middle of the night.
Come on, that's not funny. I don't like it
if someone plays tricks on
me, even if it's my grandson.
This is not a prank.  This is war.
You are not waging war
against your family, you are
against the enemy.
And I'm not your enemy
You have my declaration of war.
Why did not you say anything?
Because I was hoping it was a joke.
It's not a joke. You took something
away from me and I want it back.
OK.  Go back to sleep, I got it.
But now it's over.
We'll see you tomorrow
morning, respectively, soon.
Grandpa?  I love you.
I love you too.
But the war continues.
Hello grandpa.
Hey, Jenny. -May I come inside?
Sure, why not.
Because I wasn't allowed to stay with Peter.
I always snuck in
when he wasn't around.
Come on in.
What can I do for you?
Nothing.  I am just curious.
Do you know it's my birthday soon?
Yes I know.
OK.  I just wanted to make sure.
What's this?
These are marbles.
Can i have one
Sure, but promise to take care of it.
They are special.
You are not magical.
People always say that things
are magical and they never are.
No, I didn't say they were magic
but they are special.  Come here.
You know that grandpa
used to build houses?
Yes, before I was born.
That's right, you haven't existed yet.
But if you have a
When building a house,
you always start digging first.
And for some reason you
almost always find marbles
because they roll everywhere
and are easily lost.
And with almost every building
pit that I've dug, I have
found a marble or two.
Guess what I did.
What?
You collected.
And now if you count all these marbles
do you know how
many houses i built.
That's a lot of houses.
I also worked a long time.
Why don't you work now
Because I'm retired now.
What is retirement
That's when you stop working
and can do other things.
Your grandmother
and I had many plans
but, sometimes it turns out
differently than you think.
Can I have a marble now?
Yes.
Watch out, little mouse, watch out.
Are you okay, Grandpa?
Yes / Yes.
I'm just resting a little down here.
Do I still get a marble?
Take what you want
Oh no no no no
What's that noise up there?
Grandpa lost his marbles.
"Come to my room. Immediately."
You wanted to see me? -Yes.
Come in. Close the door.
Sit down.
So, you know the jar
with all my marbles?
No. How should I know
what you've got here
in your room...?  That used to be mine.
It's good. That's funny.
Very funny, actually.
Everyone likes pranksters.
I thought we were through.
Just tell mom and
dad you got the room
want to trade with me.
Then it's done.
You really want war?
Because I participated in one.
It's not like video games.
Even if you win,
others will be hurt.
I just want what's mine
And do you play with fire?
I do not play.
Okay. And what are the
rules of the whole thing?
What?
We need rules about what
is allowed and what is not.
There are no rules in war.
-Oh yes, and if.
"Rule number one:
no collateral damage
the civilian population
or their property. "
That means it shouldn't endanger
your parents or your sisters.
I Agree.
"Rule number two: don't talk about it."
BEHAVIOUR RULES
This is hand to hand. Just between the
two of us. Nobody betrays the other.
I Agree.
OK.  Sign!
All right, your wish comes
true, "Secret Warrior".
OK.  "Old Soldier".
From now on: "Take better care".
The jungle: big and small,
exotic and live here
bizarre animals in the same place and
at the same time next to each other.
The game is called: survival.
The use: eat or be eaten.
Those who attack
first get another one
Enjoy the day.
Those who sleep will be eaten.
OK.  Okay.
What kind of stuff is that?
"Quick drying assembly foam" .
I'll kill him.
Don't mess with me, you little...
Do you think you're smart?
Then you did the math without
the landlord, my friend.
You will be sorry for
that, I promise you.
Do you think you're smart?  Not even close!
Nobody will ever know!
I don't know what you are talking about.
You're doing very well, Grandpa.
Thank you, little mouse.
You are a very good teacher.
Why is your face so red
I dont know.
Maybe I'm allergic to
something in this house.
Well, I'll be in the shaving cream then.
I mean... school.
Uh, Peter!  is that your folder?
Yes, thank you.
Have fun at school, kid.
I love you.
Hey pete How's your super
unnecessary war going?
Not good. I was awake the whole night.
could not sleep.
Diarrhea?
What?  No!  My grandpa.
Your grandfather has diarrhea?
No! There is no
diarrhea in history.
I did everything you said and
got him hit a few times too.
This morning I put
Tabasco in his coffee.
Until now nothing.
Dude, your grandfather works with psy-ops.
Psychological warfare.
Or, he's just grown up.
Peter? When you've chatted
enough, you'll want us
maybe read your essay
about your summer vacation?
Yes, sure.
"My Summer Vacation" by Peter Decker.
This summer vacation was
the best I've ever had.
I've ridden a lot and
haven't showered anymore
until I stunk like a monkey's bottom.
Please read on, Peter.  Go ahead.
I do not want.  This is not my...
Read
I figured out how to freeze
my own farts in a bag.
I didn't write that.
Sit down again.
We'll talk to each other after class.
Psy-ops.
Amateur.
What's going on here?
Uh, nothing, nothing at all!  We only have...
I brought her some
vocabulary exercises.
Really?
Vocabulary.
Russell, get out!  Mia, you stay.
What about the rule that says no
Boys are allowed into the
house when nobody is around?
Oh, my god, mom, don't blow your mind.
We didn't do anything.
I used to be your age too.
You? I can not imagine. -Oh no?
No. You are already... -What?
You already are, you are...
Say it.
The vocabulary exercises
really paid off, honey.
What the hell...!
Well, you started it, kid.
He got me full.
I got him full.
Tape at the end of the door,
as if I wouldn't smell something
like that for a hundred meters.
Beginner!
-Tesa at the end of the door.
It really doesn't get any more stupid.
Go back, I'll tee off.
Yes.  I'm already gone.
Let's skip the hole.
Good idea. -Yes.
I wonder how Grandpa
is doing golf.
My Jordans!
Dude, I think your
grandpa must be a ninja.
My Jordans.
The first time?
To my chagrin, no.
What are you, a spy or something?
No. I'm just trying to
outsmart my grandson.
We are in the middle
of a war for his room.
I just moved in
with my daughter...
No, don't say anything. Then nobody
can force me to testify against you.
I am mute.
I help you.
Give me one last try.
Oh, stupid...
What am I doing wrong again?
Oh no no You have to go through it on
your own, otherwise you will never learn.
Do you like that?
Well, you see, it's okay.
Bam! Cars like this VW
Beetle from 1974...
We had one like that too.
The clutch was broken
and we replaced it.
I know. You dropped
the flywheel on my toe.
Themselves to blame.
I wasn't the son you always wanted.
Don't we want to look at
something else? Maybe...
Netflix?
The weather channel?
Home shopping?
Oh yes, "the Grinch", please.
Good idea!
Hey, I'm going over to Skyler's.
What?  Now?
Yes, for learning.
You want me to go to a
good college don't you?
Okay, see you.
She's seeing Russell, I know that.
What?
-It's none of my business.
Spit it out before you choke on it.
OK.
Just don't start a fight
with her about her boyfriend.
With you it took me two years.
Yes.
When you started dating Artie.
I don't know anything about that.
But I.  It was awful.
I was always at home.
Yes, you were at home talking to
your mother. You never came to me.
Really? -Yes.
Excuse me.
-No, it's okay, it was my fault.
I thought he wasn't good
enough for you until I realized
that that wasn't the point.
You said he was good enough for you.
But,
now you get on well together.
Because I pull myself together.
But, I will always
miss these two years.
Wow!  Yes, thank you very much, Ed.
I've come to terms with you.
I mean that very seriously.
But as for your career...
What?  Dad!
Nothing against Artie, I just think that
people who get their dreams out of the
Losing eyes and settling for
less, never being happy.
Really? Well, I think the same
people value a secure income.
Which then enables them to take
in their aging father-in-law.
And my name is "Arthur".
Come on, sparrow time for bed. March off.
Night, little mouse.
Night. -Good night.
You did a great job again.
sorry.
I can't reassemble anything.
He has all of them
Screws hidden.
Now I have to sleep on the floor.
That's really funny.
Yes.  Haha.
Dude, you may have to admit that
you're not as smart
as your grandfather.
Billy, wicked snake.
Thank you.
Steven, the dog was chewing
on your underpants again.
These are not mine.
Really not? "Captain Steve"
is written on the waistband.
Make you come out!
"Captain Steve".
You see, it's very easy.
Yeah thank you baby
And now, out with you.
You have helped me a lot.
Well, who said it?
I know what you could do, Peter.
-So what?
You could use some of your
mental energy that you waste on
Using stupid pranks on your grandpa
to get rid of your 4 in math.
Who cares about math?
This is real life.
... says the guy who builds a
virtual castle in a video game.
Petersburg is not a
castle, it is a palace.
And after almost three years of
construction, it is as good as finished.
Keep on dreaming.
Ah no.  Oh!
And then see if the
light is on again.
No no no!
Every beginner knows that.
What was that?
GRANDPA'S COOKIES
Do you have them with you?
Do you have the money
You don't need to count.
I know, Pete.  I trust you.
Not funny, Peter!
Don't hurt me, I won't hurt you either!
You can do what you want,
only: don't bite me!
You know what, I'm just going over here.
You don't mind, Eddie.
Stay away.  Stay away.  Stay away!
What's this?
An emergency chain.
A what?  Like the ones from advertising?
You want me to wear this? It's out of
the question. No way. I'd rather die.
You know you can wear them under your
shirt and nobody will see anything.
It's great.
Dad, if you don't want to wear
it for yourself, wear it for me.
But I don't need that.
-Really not?
If I tell you
Because Arthur meant that you
would have acted very strangely.
Oh yes?
For your information:
I didn't say "strange".
I said, "extremely confused".
"Confused".
Dad, is it so hard to
believe that we're worried
to make you You probably
never need to use them.
That's right,
because I'll never wear it.
Dad, it would just comfort
me to know that you are with
Get help when you need it
with the push of a button.
You're welcome.
Nice necklace, Grandpa.
Just watch out, my friend.
And that's how you found him?
Yes. I couldn't reach him
online and was worried.
My life's work, a ruin.
That's just a pile of rubble.
He ruined Petersburg.
I've built on it for more
than a third of my life.
Strictly speaking,
three twelfths are exactly 25 percent,
that's less than a
third of your life.
That's how it is.
Everything will be fine.
Ah, I was right, honey.
The little one slowly comes to his senses.
Do you both promise
to only use words?
Promised.
Why do we have to do this?
When conducting peace talks,
you need a neutral mediator
otherwise it degenerates
into screaming at some point.
This is stupid!
It took me five
minutes to get on this
To sit down in a chair,
I'm not getting up again.
Grandpa promised.
Now you have to promise.
Okay good.  I promise it.
Well. So, the hostilities
are getting stronger
ran the rudder than anyone
could have foreseen.
You don't mess with
someone else's computer.
That's not cool!
Everything is allowed in war, kid.
War! I just want my room back!
Don't shout!
I don't do that at all, he screams.
Apologize to Grandpa.
No, leave it alone, little mouse.
Love you, Grandpa.
-Love you too.
Stop it! -With what?
What's going on here?
-Nothing's going on here.
You should be neutral!
I don't even know what that means.
You can't pretend that you
like him better than me.
But I like him better than you.
He gave me a cookie.
Okay, that sounds worse than it is.
Right, a biscuit has changed hands
but long before this
trial was scheduled.
With chocolate chips.  My favorite variety.
My Also.
Okay, that's enough.
The peace is canceled.
Don't shout!
Fuck it all!
You don't say "Fuck it"!
Peter.
Do I get my second cookie now?
Peter, now please wait. That cookie
was wrong. So maybe I wanted to
Influence the mediator, which in
hindsight was somewhat inappropriate.
"Somewhat inappropriate"?
Come on be honest,
you have a preconceived opinion
went into this negotiation.
You didn't want to give peace a chance.
What for?
You destroyed Petersburg.
But that's what I was
trying to tell you.
War isn't just any game, Peter.
Only children,
fools and generals think so. War hurts.
War wounds, kills and causes misery.
We have to end this somehow.
And how?
How about one last competition
and the winner gets everything?
What kind of competition?
I have no idea, choose something.
I do what you want and
then the spook is over.
What I want?
-Whatever you want.
OK.
It's not a rendezvous.
We are missing the fourth in the team,
it has to be a woman and
I don't know anyone else.
Just a moment.
They want me to be
Help you get your
grandson to the cart
to drive because the two of you
can't live peacefully under one roof?
You can also put it that way.
I will participate. Sometimes my
granddaughter robs me of the last nerve.
Oh heaven we're dead
Intimidation tactic,
that's all there is to it, Danny.
Just don't show them your fear.
That makes them strong.
They are like baby velociraptors.
Yes, exactly, velociraptors.
Do you even remember
how to play dodgeball?
Was there a dodgeball in the century?
There have been smart asses, I know that.
And remember not to aim for the head.
Not even on the eggs.
Spare the crown jewels.
You heard him.
Do you have your adhesive cream with you, old
man? Your wrong bit is about to take off.
Big words for a baby.
Do you want to change your diaper first?
No you maybe
Men! -Who are you telling that.
You'll love the attic, Grandpa.
Don't be too early,
my little one.
It starts! -It starts!
Yes!
Hello!
Run for your life!
Fire!
Why did I get involved in this?
Man on the ground.
Hey, not upside down, we said!
Oops.  Has slipped away.
And from!  Teenage Team: One.
Senior team: zero.
My ears are ringing.  That is barbaric.
Shut up, Danny, pull yourself together.
Who is this?
Come here guys.
It looks like they're
way too fast for us.
We have to play our own way
if we are to win. Am I right?
Yes. -Yes / Yes.
I have an idea.  So,...
Game two!  On your places!
Grab them!
Fire!
Yes.  Now you have a problem.
Boom!
Out! Out! Out! Caught twice, one hit.
Three points.
Come, you seemingly dead, show me!
Well, if that's not Mr. Headshot!
In the balls.
Oops.  Has slipped away.
End of game two. A draw. Last match.
The winner gets it all.
Are you okay again?  Come here.
On your places!
What is he up to?
Danny!
You are an animal!
Shit yeah  Whose house is this?
Our house! -Our house!
Yes!
Final sprint!
Jerry!  What about you?
Something broke.
It pinged loudly.
Age!
I mean old dude are you okay
But sure it is, stupid.
Jerk.
You!  Out!
Shit!
Hey, you can't get me, I'm on fire!
Sorry, Danny!
Oh, it was on purpose.
You two, get out!
What?
That's unfair.
Yeah, that doesn't count. The boy was
already out and he throws like a chick.
Diane, that was fire from our own ranks.
Are you playing for the enemy now?
You three, get out!
Sorry, Peter's grandpa,
but now you are due!
Where is the female solidarity?
Sorry, little one.
You weren't shot down for nothing.
This is so stupid.
Yes / Yes.  You're out, get out!
Show him, Ed! -Yes.
Go on, Peter! -Finish him!
Get your room back.
-Yes exactly!
Show him what's a rake, Ed!
-Go on, Ed!
What are you waiting for?
Go now Next comes an eighth birthday.
A draw!
That doesn't exist! -No!
What? No way! I caught his
ball before it caught mine.
I caught his first.
Seriously, he caught him before him.
-He dropped his.
Not true at all.
He has butter fingers. Here please.
He is old.
His fingers don't work.
The finger works.
Okay, that's enough. The game is over.
Goes home. All of them, seriously.
I have won.  You lost.
What are you talking about?
I clearly caught the ball in front of you.
Is there a bar here by any chance?
What's this?
I just scribble.
This doesn't look like
one of your usual "boxes".
Yes.
I find it interesting and
really very beautiful. For work?
No, the city has put out
a tender for an extension
the library and I thought
I'd submit my draft.
But you know how it is. They always
choose one of the big companies.
100 percent of the shots on goal
that you don't try don't go in.
You know who said that?
Uh no.
Wayne Gretzky.
Best ice hockey player in the world.
I was just about to say that.
The great?
The biggest.
Still not a sports fan?
No.
Is good.
Over here! -Ready to sedate!
Just lie there, sir.
What do you want from me?
-Quiet, sir!
We'll save your life, sir.
Holds him tight!
I just bought it, you idiot!
Don't panic, sir,
you are in good hands!
Get rid of that thing or you're dead!
Patient defends himself.
We may need fixations.
Hold still, sir. Relax sir!
Wow, this test was difficult.
I found it very easily.
Come on, get in.
Uh, thanks, but I think I'd rather
go by bus - with my friends.
Come on now, get in.
Until tomorrow.
a friend of yours?
This is chuck.
You don't need to know more about him.
Um...
Where are we going?
Clear Lake.  Nice there, you'll like it.
You already know that I'm only 12?
I still have my whole life ahead of me.
Maybe one day I'll be president.
Or be the first person to fly to Mars.
Holy hoe!
Get out!
You know mom is expecting us for dinner.
Maybe I should call her
and tell her where we are.
Don't worry,
we'll bring dinner with us.
I rented it for a couple of hours.
I thought,
let's do something
together and go fishing.
Does that sound good?
Very good.
It's definitely boring.
I do not think so.
One took a bite.
Pull him up!
Seems like a lot. Hey
It's huge!
Come here Yes.
This is not a fish, this is a whale.
He put up a lot of resistance.
We're all fed up tonight.
I'll give you some new bait.
Thank you.
OK.  And eject!
Really really good.
Thank you.  Kind of fun.
Yes do it. That's what happens
when you bury the hatchet, you see?
How do they bite?
Pretty good.  I caught some nice ones.
I'm happy for you.
That is definitely because
that not too many people fish here.
Because it's forbidden.
What? -What?
You can ask the ranger.
Here he comes.
Throw the fish out! -But why?
Overboard with it!
How so? -Make it up!
The cool box!
Forget the cool box.
You're breaking the law!
He's catching up with us.
That's right, he's catching up with us.
What are you doing there?
I'll call Chuck to pick us up.
Did he leave us behind?
What kind of friend is that?
Friend? He is my driver.
I don't know the guy.
Stop immediately or you
will face the consequences!
Hold on, the landing will be tough.
Hurry up!
Why didn't you tell us
that fishing is prohibited?
I wanted to rent the boat!
Stop!  Stop!
That was so cool. -Yes, it was.
But breaking the law is
wrong, you know that.
Yes.  I know that.
Stop here, chuck.
I want to show you something, Pete.
I built this house,
which is now empty.
The color is different, I don't like it.
What do you think?
I think it's good.
Maybe you are right.
You know, over the years,
when I wasn't in a good mood
I drove over and looked inside.
I've seen the people live in my
den, raise their children
lead their lives and
have I felt better.
Do you feel better now?
Yes absolutely.
Should I tell you a secret?
Yes. -Then come with me.
People who build houses
usually sign their work,
just like artists do their paintings.
Really?
Yes, but always only hidden.
Some write their names on a
rafter, some hide one
Newspaper with the date the house
was finished under the floorboards.
One always has a poem
at the bottom of one
Toilet written before
he installed it.
What did you do?
I always had one of my men take
a picture of me and your grandma.
I built that into the wall
next to the fireplace.
That's why there are
everywhere in this part of town
Photos of me and your
grandma on the walls.
What nobody but you know
Now you know.
That's cool.
You will become a real angler.
Maybe next time we will find a
lake where fishing is allowed...
... and which is
teeming with perch.
Oh, really fat.
-Yes, murderous things.
Grandpa? -Yes, Pete?
Thank you for fishing with me today.
I had a lot of fun.
You are welcome. I had a lot of fun too.
Let's do this more often.
Yes.  Gladly.
I'll see you below.
Great.  Got me
And properly.  You are a dead man
Upps. -Aua!
Well, something like that too.
No, not again.
Oops.  But something like that too.
The Santa hat goes right here.
Have you already finished writing them?
I'm still there.
"Come and celebrate her super fun birthday
party with Jennifer. Motto: Christmas"
Great.  Very good.
Do you like it?
Absolutely.
Forgiveness?  Is this busy?
Thanks for coming with me. You never
like to go alone on such occasions.
Carl and I have had many
adventures together.
He'll be missing, the old warrior.
How is he...?  You already know...
Fell asleep.  When skydiving.
You look good bro.
Are you here alone, madam?
This is my husband.
I could drive you home.
What the...
Sorry.
Crap.
What?  Damn it!
I'm really sorry, Carl.
I don't know the guy.
Then tell me.
How was the funeral yesterday?
Really nice.  Thanks for asking.
And with you?
Something exciting is going on at school.
No. Unless you name a huge one
Eighth graders getting
punched in the face, exciting.
Really?
Yes.
How did it come about?
He got a full load of orange
juice when he opened my backpack.
Crazy isn't it?
Hi Guys.
Hey dad
I'll turn the stuff off for a
moment, then I'll help you
to put the lights on the roof, Ed.
Thank you Arthur.  I said "Arthur".
You both make a good team.
Jenny's birthday is going to be so great.
Now we just need one
for early September
Find Santa Claus and
everything will be perfect.
Forget Santa Claus. I know him personally.
Consider it done.
Thanks dad.  Sweet of you.
That's the least I can do.
Mom, before you say "no", listen to me.
Can I invite Russell
to Jennifer's party?
No. -What?
Why not?  Peter's friends are coming too.
It occurs to me that I
invited Jerry and the gang.
Yes, that is fine.
Don't you see how unfair that is?
I hate you!
I don't want to hear it.
Hey peter?
Yes?
Listen... In World War I, the Germans and
the British have theirs on Christmas Eve
Arms down to celebrate the holiday
instead of shooting the enemy.
Your sister's birthday is a special
occasion and should be celebrated.
I guess you are right
Then we agree on a
temporary truce for Jenny.
Yes?
I Agree.
Ouch!
Oh, stop it!  You hurt me  Au.
Looks like fun.
Yes, great fun.
We also like to have fun.
I forgot, I have to detention.
Now you are alone  I have a question.
Do you know my grandson, Peter Decker?
I thought to myself.
Into the trash. -What?
It's getting easier
without resistance, kid.
Come on, fat man.
Shit who are you?
-Shut your mouth!
Disciplinary Committee.
Leave Peter alone, understand?
Phew, overripe. Not your lucky
day, fat bastard. In with you
No!  No!  Not!  No!
How disgusting!
Get me out of here!  Hello?
Wow!
Happy birthday, sparrow.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, JENNIFER!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
It is quiet.  Too calm.
Billy, you have a truce. His grandpa
will certainly not do anything.
And if it does, I'm prepared.
Do you see the throne there?
CHRISTMAS WORKSHOP
Got a booby trap installed.
Somebody here should blow up?
Take off, Steve.
This eggnog tastes like nothing.
We can change that immediately.
Watch out guys!  Guess Who's Here!
Ho Ho Ho! Merry Christmas,
Santa Claus is here!
Yes, Santa Claus! -Juchhu!
Not so stormy,
I've got enough for everyone.
Toys and sweets.
What a child's heart desires.
Wait a moment.  This is not my grandpa.
Ed?
No thanks. I have to pay attention.
You never know.
The little one wouldn't dare to do that.
You shook hands with it.
No, these children
cannot be trusted.
Hey grandpa.
Hey  Nice party, what buddy?
Yes, super cool. But I thought
you were playing Santa Claus?
I? Oh no,
I leave that to the pros.
Jerry has been giving Santa since
he retired. Is that a problem, Pete?
Why a problem?
I'm only asking. Hey, would you be
so nice and bring me some water?
Thanks, kid.
The boy is up to something, I can feel it.
Certainly just a coincidence.
Ho Ho Ho. And what's your name?
Let me guess. 20 years ago
it wasn't a name. I'm right?
Peter? -Dad, what's up?
Do you know where Mia is?
She should help me with the hot dogs.
No I do not know.
-Okay, you help me then.
Hey grandpa.
What happened to you You are all wet.
There are no answers to some questions.
Hey, a cookie?
No not now. -They're delicious.
Thank you, I really don't want one.
-Especially this one.
I do not like. -For sure?
Absolutely safe.
Please put mustard and
ketchup on those things
and bring them to guests
before they get cold?
Sure, dad. I take over in the
front and you in the back?
You are the boss.
Oh man i'm sorry I slipped.
I swear it wasn't on purpose.
There is nothing you can do.
Oh damn.
The bottles must be too full.
Hey dad? The lighting gives up its
ghost, you check it out?
Yes I do.
And Peter, will you check on the
compressor for the bouncy castle?
It could be a little plumper.
What is the lad up to?
Grandpa!
Dad!
Dad are you hurt
I'm good.
Found a quarter of a dollar.
Peter, we said no pranks.
We shook hands with it.
What happened?
What are you two talking about?
Grandpa,
I swear I didn't do anything!
Santa Claus is dead.
Okay, maybe I was.
That is not good at all.
Danny, Ed,...
Did you see that?  That was awesome.
Here comes Santa Claus.  Ho Ho Ho!
My sausages!
Jerry!  Everything okay?
Where am I?
Fire!
Get to safety!  I delete.
I'll get the garden hose.
Is good.  OK.  I have a pen...
"From the face..." I'm
blind, I'm blind!
I do that!
Grandpa, get out of the way!
My Christmas tree!
My Christmas birthday cake!
Oh, what have we done?
No no!
Peter!
Hi mom.
Mia?  Russell?
Don't you dare run away, Russell!
Nothing happened.
Okay, and I can't help it.
Hey, could someone help me?
That's a pretty deep
scratch, Mr. Marino.
You should see the tree first.
Thank you.
What? What? There is nothing.
I'm fine.
Sure you are fine.
You are always fine.
Nobody should help you
in any way or love you.
Sally, please stop.
You could have been dead!
Come on, don't make it a drama now.
It was an accident and nothing more.
An accident? -Yes.
Do you seriously think I don't
know anything about the "war"?
Dad... or should I say "old soldier"?
Oh, oh that.
What did you guys think?
Don't blame the boy.
It's up to me alone.
I'm an adult,
I should have known better.
God knows yeah
I'm so sorry.
It got out of hand.
I have enough money to pay for everything.
I'll get my old crew and
we'll fix everything.
It's not about the
house or the money, Dad.
If you hated staying with us so
much, you should have said it.
I never said I hated you guys.
Exactly, you never told us.
Yeah, I never said it.
Have we got that sorted out now?
No!  Forget what you never said
I was just thinking, when you come to
us, you will notice that we
love you and change your
mind about living alone.
But of course it didn't come to that.
You are so keen on it...
...To have fun.
Are you okay, Grandpa?
-Yes, I'm fine.
I'm sorry about what happened
at your birthday party.
It's okay. I have something for
you to make you feel better.
That's kind of you.
But I gave it to you, remember?
Don't you want her?
I think you need her more
But it's only on loan.
That's very grown up of
you, my darling.
You can take it home with you soon.
The doctor just
looks at the x-rays.
We are waiting for you outside.
Can I see him now?
No. It will be a long time
before we both get you back
leave together alone.
Maybe never.
Will he get well again?
Naturally. As for you and
Mia, that's a different story.
You are under labor arrest
for the next six months.
Work arrest?  What is that, please?
Room arrest plus household chores.
For six months.
What? -Yes.
Well, it adds up a lot, doesn't it?
I haven't done half as much as Peter.
That is so unfair.
Will I also get work arrest?
No, honey, you don't.
Russell!
You will please stay seated!
What?  Wait.  Mom!
Russell ?!
Dad, can't you see her senses...
Russell!
You should stay seated, Mia.
Leave me in peace!
Come here now, you coward!
Come here!
Okay, that's enough. Mom is
definitely crazy. I have to go there.
Wait. I know your mother.
She's getting herself back.
You don't hit me, do you Mrs. Decker?
No.
What are you up to?
What I'm not going to do is lose
two years with my daughter, Russell.
Take my hand before
I change my mind.
Come by tomorrow.
Really?
Yes.  And bring work clothes.
I have a huge hole on the first floor.
That needs to be fixed.
OK.
And everything is alright?
Thank you mom.
I didn't hurt him.
Everything will be fine.
Let's get Grandpa and go home.
Excuse me, could you see if
Mr. Marino can go home yet?
Oh, it's long gone.
I assumed they were all gone.
He said his brother would pick him up.
Brothers?
Yes.  Chuck...?
Chuck.
Who is chuck
Dad?
Ed?
Grandpa!  Grandpa!
Grandpa!
Mom!
Jerry doesn't know where he is either.
I shouldn't have
pushed him so hard.
It's Peter's fault.
Grandpa is gone because of him.
Yes peter But now you have your room back.
Are you happy?
Peter?  Wake up.
I think I know where Grandpa is.
I also like the fireplace a lot. Something
like that is no longer built today.
Thank you.
Secrets hide behind these walls.
Wait!
I started it,
I want to finish it too.
Hi Chuck.
Grandpa! -Peter.
So what's going on?
You moved out of your room.
It's your room, kid.
It always has been.
I've decided I want
you to have it.
I don't want you to go away, Grandpa.
We both know that the room
will always be between us.
No it won't.
I also love the attic.
I don't know why I was so mad
about the old, smelly room.
Honest. Grandpa,
you have to come back please.
It's not that easy.
I do everything too. I'll bring you
every single marble back, I swear.
Oh, Pete.
Grandpa, please.
You don't even know how ashamed I am.
I just want to hide somewhere.
It's all my fault.
No, don't believe that for a second.
We were both to blame.
You only defended what was yours.
Maybe a war like that
starts and goes on and on.
Your enemy does something bad to you,
so you do something worse to him.
And he takes revenge, and you take revenge.
And the whole thing
gets worse and worse.
And at some point someone
just drops a bomb.
That's how it works, isn't it?
Yes, that's how it works.
I never want to go to war.
I am very glad you said that.
And I hope to God that
you never have to either.
Should I tell you something?
Somehow I enjoyed measuring
myself against you.
Really?
Yes. I could forget my
grief for your grandma.
And... you got me pretty
bad a couple of times.
Well, you me too.
Yes.
Please come home, Grandpa.
Come here.
3 MONTHS LATER
Well, Mr. Decker,
if you'd sign here then.
I actually wanted to
cut the tree myself.
But my wife has an
aversion to chainsaws.
I can use the
chainsaw at any time.
I believe you, man.
And if you still
what need call me at the
office, yes?
I mean,
I can use the chainsaw anytime.
A little more dignity, please.
It's just a chainsaw. How so?
Did she say something?
Hey grandpa.
I am ready to go fishing.
Oh, Petey, I forgot to tell you.
Fishing has to be canceled today.
How so? We always go fishing on Saturdays.
This is our thing.
I know this is it. Unfortunately, I have
other plans now. I'll make it up to you.
And how?
Maybe we'll go to the cinema
or that new ice cream parlor.
Ah, you see, this is for me.
I have to go. We make something.
Is something wrong?
Because of Peter.
Let's go.
Grandpa!  Grandpa!
Hi, grandpa.
There! -His fingers don't work!
No.  Better this way.
Too much? -  It fits!
Oh!  Sorry!
Once again.
I see you're doing...
Nice, stimulates blood circulation.
Russell!  Russell!  Russell!
You have to cut that out.
Shit sorry.
I've got a frog in my throat.
I want to be an opera singer.
How did he move?
The guy is still alive.
In the next episode you will see...
Again, right?
Hey can i help you?
Can i sniff you?
Can i help you sir
-Puff, absolutely. Yes!
No, it doesn't do anything.  Moment...
Oh, come on now.
-  Well, again.
What don't you do.
-  That's life.
And you can drive that thing?
Shit yeah  Fun!  S-P- and A-S-S.
You should be able to spell.
What was that now?
You were in the marines?
Nonsense.  I just mean.
You are so silly.
In with you!
Shit who are you
Ok, it's in the box!
... I would work for a
soulless group of companies
who are not interested in the
worries and needs of their...
Okay, cut.Was good.
Thank you too.